<resources>
    <string name="app_name">East London Guide</string>
    <string name="category_tower">Tower</string>
    <string name="category_riverside">Riverside</string>
    <string name="category_isleOfDogs">Isle of Dogs</string>
    <string name="category_eastEnd">East End</string>
    <string name="showLocation">Show Map</string>

    <!-- Tower of London -->
    <string name="tower_name1">Tower of London</string>
    <string name="tower_description1">The Tower of London was begun by William the Conqueror
        in 1078 to replace a temporary wooden structure put up not long after the Battle of
        Hastings in 1066. The first building to be erected was the central keep, which had
        walls 15 ft (4.6 m) thick and reached a height of 90 ft (27 m). It was renamed the
        White Tower after being whitewashed in 1240.\nBy the time Edward I completed the
        building work at the end of 13th century the outer wall enclosed an area of 18 acres
        (1.3 ha).\nIn 1235 the Holy Roman Emperor gave Henry III three leopards, in honour
        of the leopards on the Plantagenet coat of arms, and there were the start of the Royal
        Menagerie at the Tower.\nThe Last monarch to occupy the Tower was James I. The last
        man to be executed on Tower Hill was Jacobite peer, the 11th Lord Lovat, in 1747.</string>
    <string name="tower_location1">geo:51.508054,-0.0789826,16.54z</string>

    <!-- Tower Bridge -->
    <string name="tower_name2">Tower Bridge</string>
    <string name="tower_description2">Tower Bridge is often mistaken for London Bridge.
        Opened in 1894, it was the last of Victorian bridges across the Thames and is
        London\'s only bridge that opens.\nFor the first few years of its life the bridge
        was opened several times a day. Approaching ships would hoot their horn when they
        reached Cherry Pier downstream, as a signal that they wished to come through. Today,
        24 hours\' notice is required for the bridge to open. In 1952 a crowded double-decker
        bus was caught on the bridge as it started to open and the driver had no choice but
        to accelerate and jump the gap.</string>

    <!-- Wilton's Music Hall -->
    <string name="tower_name3">Wilton\'s Music Hall</string>
    <string name="tower_description3">Wilton\'s Music Hall is the oldest surviving
        music-hall in the world.\nIt started life as a small saloon theatre in the back room
        of a pub called the Prince of Denmark, but nicknamed as the Mahogany Bar because it
        was the first pub in London to have mahogany fittings. In 1850 John Wilton bought the
        pub and expanded the saloon, calling it Wilton\'s Music Hall.\nToday Wilton\'s is run
        by the Wilton\'s Music Hall Trust and puts on plays, operas, exhibitions and readings.
        The hall has been left virtually untouched in all its faded, Victorian glory, with the
        paint peeling and the lighting dim.</string>

    <!-- Shadwell -->
    <string name="riverside_name1">Shadwell</string>
    <string name="riverside_description1">The Prospect of Whitby is one of London\'s
        oldest riverside pubs - there has been a tavern here since at least 1520.
        Frequented by every kind of smuggler and villain, the place became known as
        \'Devil\'s Tavern\' until it burned down in the 18th century. It was rebuilt and
        took the name Prospect of Whitby from a collier which used to moor outside the inn
        and became something of a local landmark.\nThe huge red-brick building with a tall
        square tower, opposite the Prospect of Whitby, was built as a pumping station for the
        London Hydraulic Power Company.The tower, known as an accumulator tower, was pumped full
        of water during off-peak hours by steam pumps. The water raised a weighted plunger filled
        with stones, ready to provide power during busy periods. This particular building was the
        last of the hydraulic pumping stations to shut down, finally closing in 1977. It is now a
        cafe and exhibition centre laid put around the old turbines, and there is an unusual
        viewing platform on the roof.</string>

    <!-- King Edward Memorial Park -->
    <string name="riverside_name2">King Edward Memorial Park</string>
    <string name="riverside_description2">Kind Edward Memorial Park was opened in 1921
        on the site of a former fish market and is one of the few places in docklands
        to have survived unchanged into the new millennium. The river views are wide and
        splendid, and down by the waterfront is a round, red-brick building covering an air shaft
        for the Rotherhithe Tunnel, which runs underneath the park. On the wall is a tablet
        commemorating four Elizabethan explorers who \'in the latter half of the sixteenth
        century set sail from this reach of the River Thames near Retcliffe Cross\'.</string>

    <!-- Limehouse -->
    <string name="riverside_name3">Limehouse</string>
    <string name="riverside_description3">Limehouse takes its name from the many lime
        kilns that were located here from the 14th century onward, burning chalk brought
        up the river from Kent, and producing lime for London\'s building industry.\nIt was the
        location of London\'s first Chinatown, where Chinese sailors arriving on ships bringing
        tea from China settled in the area during the late 19th and early 20th century. Limehouse
        acquired a somewhat exaggerated reputation for opium dens and white slavery which fired
        the imagination of the writers of the day.\nAfter Limehouse was badly bombed in the Blitz,
        Chinatown moved west to Soho.</string>

    <!-- Canary Wharf -->
    <string name="isle_of_dogs_name1">Canary Wharf</string>
    <string name="isle_of_dogs_description1">Canary Wharf, originally constructed in 1937
        for handling cargoes of fruit from Canary Islands, is now the most visible sign of
        the immense regeneration happaning in London\'s docklands, which began in the mid
        1980s and is still spreading eastward, despite a few financial hiccups along the way.
        \nCanary Wharf appears in the Guinness Book of Records as the largest commercial
        development in the world, and now features three of the tallest buildings in Britain.
        One Canada Square, which at 771 ft (235 m) high, was for 20 years the tallest building
        in Britain.\nThe two 19th-century warehouses along the West India Quayside are the only
        original warehouses to survive wartime bombing and now contain expensive apartments,
        restaurants, bars ans a museum.</string>

    <!-- Island Gardens -->
    <string name="isle_of_dogs_name2">Island Gardens</string>
    <string name="isle_of_dogs_description2">Island Gardens were laid in 1895 by the
        Commissioners of the Royal Naval Hospital at Greenwich, both to improve their
        own view across the river from the hospital, and to give a spectacular vantage-point
        from which to see Wren\'s masterpiece in its full majesty. The result is possibly the
        most noble and glorious view on the whole of the Thames. The round, glass-domed red-brick
        building on the edge of the gardens gives access to the Greenwich foot tunnel. </string>

    <!-- Trinity Buoy Wharf -->
    <string name="isle_of_dogs_name3">Trinity Buoy Wharf</string>
    <string name="isle_of_dogs_description3">Trinity Buoy Wharf is the home of London\'s
        only lighthouse. It was built in 1864 and was used for testing maritime lighting equipment
        and for training lighthouse keepers.\nThe lighthouse and the other buildings at Trinity
        Buoy Wharf now house a variety of arts and creative industries ans event an authentic
        American diner, the Fat Boy Diner.</string>

    <!-- Whitechapel Bell Foundry -->
    <string name="east_end_name1">Whitechapel Bell Foundry</string>
    <string name="east_end_description1">Whitechapel Bell Foundry was established in 1570
        and is the oldest manufacturing company in Britain. The company moved to its present
        premises, which date from 1670 and originally housed a coaching inn called The Artichoke,
        in 1738.\nIn 1752 the foundry cast the original Liberty Bell, bearing the
        inscription\n\'PROCLAIM LIBERTY THROUGHOUT ALL THE LAND UNTO ALL THE INHABITANTS
        THEREOF\' LEV XXV X.\nThe Liberty Bell was hung in the Philadelphia State House steeple,
        but for some reason, cracked on the first ring and had to be twice recast.\nThe largest
        bell ever cast at the Whitechapel Bell Foundry is the most famous bell in the world, the
        hour bell for the Great Clock of the Westminster, \'Big Ben\', which was cast in 1858
        and rang out for the first time on 31 May 1859. </string>

    <!-- Tower House -->
    <string name="east_end_name2">Tower House</string>
    <string name="east_end_description2">Tower House is situated behind the huge East London
        Mosque. Formerly Rowton House, a lodgings place built by Disraeli\'s private secretary
        Lord Rowton, to provide cheap and safe accommodation for young men arriving in London.
        It was immortalised by Jack London in <i>The People of the Abyss</i> (1902) and by
        George Orwell in <i>Down and Out in Paris and London</i> (1933). In 1907 Iosif
        Vissarionovich Dzhugas-hvili, otherwise known as Stalin, the \'Steel One\', stayed here
        as a penniless 28-year-old student, while attending the 5th Russian Social Democratic
        Labour Party Congress, held at a venue in Fulbourne Street, opposite the Royal London
        Hospital. Others who attend the Congress were Vladimir Lenin, Leon Trotsky and Maxim Gorky.
        Tower House has recently been converted into luxury apartments for capitalist City whiz-kids.</string>

    <!-- Mile End -->
    <string name="east_end_name3">Mile End</string>
    <string name="east_end_description3">Mile End takes its name from the first milestone outside
        London\'s Aldgate, which was positioned close to where Mile End Road meets Stepney Green.
        \nOn the north side of Mile End Road are some of the most handsome buildings in the East
        End, the Trinity Almshouses. They were built in 1697 to house \'28 decayed masters and
        commanders of ships or widows of such\' and were possibly designed by Sir Christopher
        Wren and John Evelyn.\nThe explorer Captain James Cook (1728-79) and his family lived
        at No. 88 Mile End Road, almost opposite. Some of his children were born here, and it was
        from this house that he set off on his last journey. For some reason the house was
        demolished ans the site is now marked by a blue plaque.</string>
</resources>
